# **Triston Wasik**



twasik4@gmail.com



9072231825



linkedin.com/in/triston-wasik-6769aa214



https://tristonwasik.com

#### **Summary**

Experienced Software Developer/Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the government administration industry. Skilled in Customer Service, Communication, Training, Management, and Software Development. Strong engineering professional with a Associates focused in Business Administration with a focus in Programming and Development from Eastern Gateway Community College.

The mantra I follow is "the only constant is change". In technology, especially software development, everything changes all the time. Vulnerabilities are found, maintenance required, a new language or technology is founded, and etc. I enjoy this field because I love learning new technologies and find even more enjoyment in figuring out how to utilize these new technologies to solve every day problems.

# **Experience**



#### Software Engineer

**OK Candles** 

Mar 2022 - Present (4 months +)

Created the OKCandles official ecommerce website with Next.js. The website uses a Square to handle all web payments and orders, as well as managing products and stock values. The website information and content itself is managed through a Strapi.js headless CMS.

#### **Software Engineer**

Freelance

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months +)



# **Junior System Administrator**

Renegade Hosting

Nov 2012 - Present (9 years 8 months +)

Worked with users to set up Linux based virtual private servers (VPS), including answering technical queries and offering hands-on support. Completed tickets and interacted with end users in a professional manner including providing technical communications to none technical users.



#### Analyst/Programmer Flex I-IV

State of Alaska

Oct 2018 - Dec 2021 (3 years 3 months)

- Built the search functionality for the statewide internal Business Licensing system using .NET framework, Microsoft SQL Server, and Entity Framework.
- Helped maintain and improve all aspects of the Corporations, Business and Professional Licensing internal and external systems to service thousands of licensees throughout the state.
- Updated internal legacy systems to utilize RESTful APIs rather than direct database access to facilitate a merge to the Azure cloud.

- Assisted users through internal TrackIT ticketing systems with problems regarding software bugs and general maintenance requests.

# **Education**



# Eastern Gateway Community College

Associates, Business Administration with a focus in Programming and Development Sep 2020 - Dec 2021

# **Skills**

Entity Framework • jQuery UI • MySQL • prisma • MVC • GitHub • Next.js • React.js • Git